ERICA HAWKINS

4678 Willow Road · Memphis, TN 38117 · (901) 212-4845 · esykes1983@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Customer service oriented professional who provides timely and accurate data to ensure reimbursement for patient services. Follows policies, procedures and guidelines to assure consistent quality. Maintains and ensures patient privacy and confidentiality.

- Academic Honors Recognition / Honor Roll.
- Experienced with Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint, and Outlook. Type 45 WPM.

CORE QUALIFICATIONS

Medical Billing · Medical Administrative · Patient Registration · Medical Terminology

Medical Records Management · Meaningful Use

Medical Practice Management Systems · Introduction to CPT

ICD-9-CM · ICD-10-CM Coding · Charge Entry · Payment Posting · Denials · Appeals · Referrals
Accounts Receivable · Electronic Health Records (EHR) · Electronic Medical Records (EMR) · Greenway
Insurance Verification · Reimbursement Systems · Medical Basics and Healthcare Claim Cycle
Healthcare Payers · Managed Care (HMO, PPO, and POS) · Medicare / Medicaid Government Payers
Third Party Payers · HIPAA Compliance · Medical Charts · Basic Anatomy & Physiology

EDUCATION

Ultimate Medical Academy

Health Sciences – Medical Office and Billing Specialist Associate of Science Degree, 2017

WORK EXPERIENCE

Trans Recovery Solutions – Olive Branch, MS

07/2016 - Present

- **Ligation Collection Manager**
 - Resolve customer complaints and answer customers' questions regarding policies and procedures.
 - Provide employees with guidance in handling difficult or complex problems or in resolving escalated complaints or disputes.
 - Train or instruct employees in job duties and company policies.

Trans Recovery Solutions – Olive Branch, MS

10/2012 - 06/2016

Collections Manager

- Handled unpaid commercial trucking bills and kept compliant records.
- Trained new team members on company standard operating procedures.
- Handled all communications regarding assigned accounts.

Certified Credit Associated - Bartlett, TN

10/2012 - 06/2015

Leasing Sales Manager

- Met with various clients regarding collection accounts.
- Started collection process for delinquent balances.
- Utilized multi-line phone system and provided strong customer service.

Regional Adjustment Bureau - Cordova, TN

02/2008 - 09/2012

Collections Associate

- Offered support and resolution for customers with past due accounts.
- Took inbound calls, evaluated accounts, and negotiated payment solutions.